

# **Rakesh Lakshmipathy**

Email: lakshmipathy.rakesh@gmail.com

Mobile: 9962778801

Active on: Stack overflow, Blogger

#### **HIGHLIGHTS OF QUALIFICATIONS**

An accomplished software engineer offering **13+ years** with specialization in object-oriented approaches to mobile application development (**Android with both Kotlin and Java**) with the **extensive background of full lifecycle of software development processes** including requirements gathering, design, coding, testing and debugging, in addition to leading the team of size around 20.

# Strengths include:

- Android SDK (With Kotlin & Java)
- Experienced working on Architecture components
- MVVM and MVP architecture
- o Near-Field Communication (NFC) Technology
- Native Development Kit (NDK)
- o Retrofit
- Dependency Injection
- REST/ SOAP web services (JSON /XML)
- Firebase Cloud messaging and Real-time Database
- Third parties SMS integration
- o Deployments of Android applications into Google Play store
- Hangfire implementation for background recurring jobs
- Bitbucket Pipelines to enable CI/CD.
- Experience in building REST APIs with Spring Boot Framework
- Integration with BLE devices

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Android, Kotlin, Java, C#

APIs/Frameworks: Android Application Framework, Spring Boot, .NET

**O/S**: Windows, MAC OS

Databases: SQLite, SQL Server, My SQL

**Networking**: HTTP/S

Tools: Android Studio, Visual Studio, Eclipse

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant (JL5) | 10, June 2021 - till now Infosys Limited

#### **OBC(Onboard computer) For AirLiquide**

- They supply oil and gas to various industries and they are carried through the large tanker vehicles.
- o Drivers will be installing applications from Android devices with MDM setup and it is managed using WorkSpace one.
- OBC application is used to track the end to end activities since assigning a trip to a driver and till closure of a trip. The files including other text information during the trip will be captured and uploaded by drivers.
  - Provides offline support to ensure data capture even if the network bandwidth is low.

**Technical skills used:** Kotlin, Android, MVVM architecture, Hangfire(.NET background Jobs) and other third party library integrations.

#### **Home Hospital**

- o "Home hospital" simplifies the health monitoring process of a patient by Clinicians. O Patient will be holding an Android tablet and the Clinician can access both Android application and Web applications.
- The health is monitored by the vital data collected from the BLE devices such as Vital Patch, Everion, BP monitor etc.
- The data from the BLE devices are being collected by Android applications and they are synchronized to the Server.
- Patient application is available and fully controlled by MDM while Clinician application is available in Play store as well.

**Technical skills used:** Kotlin, Android, MVVM architecture, BLE integration, Firebase, Countly loggers, App socket, Third party library integrations etc

Lead Software Engineer | 08, Sep 2020 - 31, May 2021 AgnoShin Technologies Private Limited, Chennai

#### Dial2Go

- Dial2Go app will open the doors to a wide spectrum of Home maintenance services. You can avail
  of all housekeeping services starting from home cleaning, Plumbing, Electrical fittings, a/c
  maintenance, pest control and much else via the app. Appointments for your requirements can be
  scheduled as per the customer's convenience. A dedicated team of staff at Dial2go assures you of
  the best services within a strict deadline.
- Have been a sole contributor in Android development and also managed the project with an overall team size of around 15.

Technical skills used: Kotlin, Android, MVVM architecture, Room DB, Firebase, Third party libraries etc

# Team Lead | 27, Oct 2014 - 31, Aug 2020 3Edge Solutions, Chennai

# **Digital for Engineers Club (D4E Club)**

- The project idea of the National President of AIMO to connect Students, Industries, Colleges and Job Seekers.
- The mentioned category of people can post the Job or apply for the Jobs posted by Colleges/Industries.
- The Android mobile application that works in sync with Liferay Mobile SDK (version 7)
- Have been a sole contributor in Android development and also managed the project with team size of around 15.
- Launched by TN Governor: <a href="https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/chennai/a-digital-platform-to-address-unemployability/article23817489.ece">https://www.thehindu.com/news/cities/chennai/a-digital-platform-to-address-unemployability/article23817489.ece</a>

**Technical skills used:** Java, Android, Liferay Mobile SDK, MVP architecture, Firebase, Third party library integrations etc

#### **Studawn**

- Studawn is a startup with an idea / objective to help students in schools and colleges to connect with peers in their school and in other cities, to share subject notes and knowledge. Apart from academics, the Studawn helps students develop their hobbies, explore events of interest, stimulate curiosity through quizzes and competitions etc.
- Have been a sole contributor in Android development and also managed the project with team size of around 4.

**Technical skills used:** Java, Android, MVP architecture, Firebase, Third party library integrations

#### **Service Tracking System**

- Designed & developed an android native application for tracking the maintenance services on specialized medical equipment purchased by various healthcare providers in Singapore and other ASEAN countries. The services include equipment commissioning, preventive and breakdown maintenance. The application helps in scheduling service requests, capturing service details and photographs, generating work reports, capturing feedback and to monitor utilization of service personnel time.
- Online and Offline synchronizations
- Led the Mobile (Android) and Back office (Java, Angular) team towards successful project deliveries.
- Enterprise Application built for the client <u>Mandarin Opto Medic</u>

**Technical skills used:** Java, Android, MVC architecture, Third party library integrations etc

### **Mopria**

- o Designed & Developed Java and NDK based Android application for the printing process.
- The printing logic will work based on the RFC2911 standard.
- Responsible for core back-end technology development as well as UI development including analysis, design, coding, and testing for modules.
- Google Play Link: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.mopria.printplugin">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.mopria.printplugin</a>

**Technical skills used:** Java, Android, C++, MVC architecture, Third party library integrations etc

#### **PAYS**

- o It provides loyalty to the consumers by redeeming the coupons attached with the products they buy.
- PAYS also helps manufacturers and the dealers to have a long lasting relationship with the customer, knocks down the counterfeit products and protects the brand identity by generating unique coupons for each product.
- Recharge/Money transfer using Euronet APIs.
- Led the Mobile and Back office team towards successful project deliveries.
- Google Play Link: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pays.app">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pays.app</a>

Technical skills used: Ionic Framework, HTML, CSS

### **Alpha Clinical Systems**

- Designed & Developed an Android native application for tracing the patient's health
- Responsible for core back-end technology development as well as UI development including analysis, design, coding, and testing for modules.
  - Implementation of FCM to receive the notifications for filling up the forms, to receive the alerts and upcoming visits to the clinic.
  - Enterprise Application built for the client <u>Alpha Clinical Systems</u>

**Technical skills used:** Ionic Framework, HTML, CSS, FCM

# **Alpha Clinical Systems**

- Designed and developed a hybrid application using the Ionic framework for storing the patient's health data.
- Responsible for UI designing and capturing the user information such as demographics, Insurance details and making sure the patient satisfy both inclusion and exclusion criteria
- Creating multiple signature pads using canvas in one form and allowing patients and investigators to sign and generate the PDF file dynamically with the same data using pdfmake.
- Enterprise Application built for the client <u>Alpha Clinical Systems</u>

Technical skills used: Ionic Framework, HTML, C

Android Developer | 11, Apr 2013 – 31, July 2014 | KKM Soft Private Limited, Chennai.

**CTBIM** 

Designed & developed a GPS Location based Android application for the Construction tracking

Services.

• Responsible for UI designing & Core backend functions which includes the features like **REST Client** 

web services Integration, Image and Video capturing, previewing and uploading.

Enterprise Application built for the client <u>CTBIM</u>

Technical skills used: Java, Android.

**Asset Management** 

Designed & developed an Android application for tracking the working status of assets in the

various organizations

Responsible for UI designing & Core backend functions with the features includes NFC and SOAP

web service Integration, Online and offline Synchronizations.

Have had all responsibilities without any team members.

Technical skills used: Java, Android.

**Order placement** 

Designed & developed an Android application for updating the order from the retailer shops.

Responsible for UI designing & Core backend functions with the features includes NFC and SOAP

web service Integration, Online and offline Synchronizations.

Have had all responsibilities without any team members

Technical skills used: Java, Android.

**Cable TV network** 

Designed & developed an application for updating the details of Cable TV Customers including

payment, notifications, adding and removing packages for the customer

Responsible for UI designing & Core backend functions with the features includes NFC and SOAP

web service Integration, Online and offline Synchronizations.

• Have had all responsibilities without any team members

Technical skills used: Java, Android

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Engineering (Aug 2007 - Apr 2011)

Graduation in Bachelor of Engineering in (Electronics & Communication Engineering) Kanchi Pallavan Engineering College, Kanchipuram, Anna University, with 67%

# **Higher Secondary Certificate (April 2007)**

Sri Ramakrishna Mission Vidyalaya Boys Higher Secondary School, Chengalpattu, Kanchipuram DT with 68.6%

# Secondary School Leaving Certificate (Apr 2005)

Sri Ramakrishna Mission Vidyalaya Boys Higher Secondary School, Chengalpattu, Kanchipuram DT with 70 %

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

- Father's Name Lakshmipathy P
- Sex Male
- Marital Status Married
- Date of Birth 15<sup>th</sup> Feb 1990
- Nationality Indian
- **Contact Number** +91 9962778801
- Hobbies App development, Blogging, Travelling
- Languages English, Tamil and Telugu